现在，最好将使用git所做的事情看作是记录项目的历史。
Now, it's good to think of what you're doing with git as documenting the history of your project.
就像我在介绍中提到的，
And like I mentioned in the intro,
不像大多数历史学家，你有一台时光机可以让你改变历史。
unlike most historian, you have a time machine that let's you change history.
让我们来看看我们可以做的一些方法
Let's take a look at some of the ways that we can do that that.
第一个叫做修正
The 1st one is called amending.
你经常会以提交不太正确的东西而告终
You can often end up committing something that's not quite right.
您可以创建一个新的提交 但这最终会创建一个混乱的历史记录
You can create a new commit, but that ends up creating a messy history.
通过提交进行简单的修复。
With a commit for a simple fix.
要向上次提交添加内容，可以使用amend标志。
To add things to the last commit, you can use the amend flag,
当你这样做时，它会启动你的默认编辑器并允许你编辑带有修改历史的文件。
and when you do that, it's going to launch your default editor and allow you to edit the file with the amended history.
现在，如果您不想这样做，您可以输入- m标志并选择一个新的提交消息。
Now, if you don't want to do that, you can type in the minus m flag and select a new commit message.
在这里输入。
Type it in right there.
最后，如果您只想留下与上次提交时相同的消息，还可以选择no-edit功能。
Finally, you can also select the no-edit function if you just want to leave the message the same as what you did in the last commit.
让我们来看看它是如何工作的
Let's take a look at how that works.
我在docs文件夹里有这些不同的文件，
So I have these different files in the docs folder,
我意识到在我的index。html文件中，
and I realize that on my index.html file,
我有这个导航，在我的导航中，我有许多文本大写类。
I have this navigation, and in my navigation, I have a number of text-uppercase classes.
这让导航栏在某些地方变成大写。
That's making the navigation be uppercase in certain places.
不过直接放在这个nav类中会更经济。
But it would be more economical to go ahead and put that directly here in this nav class.
这样它就会影响导航区的所有内容。
That way it will affect everything inside this nav section.
我要做的就是在这里做一个改变
So what I'm going to do is make a change right here
text-uppercase，然后我要删除其他的text-uppercase实例。
text-uppercase, and then I'm going to delete the other instances of text-uppercase.
让我们继续并保存它，我们将提交这个更改。
Let's go ahead and save that, and we'll commit this change.
现在 在我完成这个之后 我意识到我真的需要在所有其他文档中这样做
Now, after I've done this, I realized that I really needed to do this in all the other documents.
所以如果我看一下我的日志 我有所有这些提交 包括我做的最后一次提交
So if I take a look at my log I have all these commits, including this last commit that I did.
现在，我要在其他文件中做的改变是完全一样的，
Now, the changes that I'm going to make in the other files are going to be exactly the same,
所以我真的不需要做新的承诺。
so I don't really need to make a new commit.
我只需要在其他文件中修复相同的东西
I just need to fix the same things in the other files.
所以我要抓住，我们看看，
So I'm going to grab, let's see,
这几行，然后到导航栏粘贴这些修改，
these lines right here, and I'll go over to the navigation and paste those changes,
确保我也来到这个导航栏，
make sure that I also come up here to this nav,
我在这里添加文本大写，我们继续复制这一行，我们要确保它被添加到这里。
and I add text-uppercase here, and we'll go ahead copy this line, and we'll make sure that that's added here.
我们也要确保这些东西都得救了。
And also we will make sure that all these things have been saved.
你可以看到这里和这里都有改动
So you can see the modifications are here and here.
如果我打开源代码控制 我可以通过点击这里来检查确保所有的修改都完成了
And if I open up source control, I can check to make sure that I've done all the changes by clicking right here.
你可以并排看到变化
And you can see the changes side by side.
visual Studio Code中的这种差异非常好。
This diffing in visual Studio Code is really nice.
你可以看到变化是同步的，前后同步，肩并肩。
And you can really see the changes synced up, before and after, side by side.
非常棒 当然 从这里 我可以打开文件 放弃更改并设置内容
Pretty awesome. Also, from here, I can, of course, open the file, discard the changes and set stuff back.
现在，我要做的是回到资源管理器
Now, what I want to do let's go back here into the Explorer
我们可以把这些关了。
we can go ahead and close these out.
然后清除这个屏幕。我想做一个“git提交-修改”。
And will clear this screen. And I want to do a "git commit --amend".
现在 这将打开我电脑上的默认编辑器
Now, this is going to open my default editor in my computer.
它被设置为Atom，它在这里所做的是让我可以修改这里的提交消息。
This is set up as Atom, and what it's doing here is given me the option of modifying the commit message here.
如果你什么都不想做 你可以把这关了
If you don't want to do anything, you can just close this.
但我要把它改成文件中的简化文本大写。
But I'm going to change it to say simplified text uppercase in files.
然后我要保存这个并关闭这个应用程序。
And then I'm going to save this and close out of this application.
当我回去的时候，它会说它已经用三次插入改变了一个文件。
And when I go back, it'll say that it went ahead and changed one file with three insertions.
让我们在这里执行“git log—online”，您可以看到它没有创建一个新的提交，它只是修改了上一次提交。
Let's go ahead and do the "git log --oneline" here, and you can see that it didn't create a new commit, it just modified the last one.
它确实更新了提交的文本，因为我在另一个文档中用其他命令更新了。
And it did update the text of the commit, because I did that in the other document with the other commands.
如果你使用git commit amend - m，你可以直接在终端中修改文本。
If you do git commit amend minus m, you can do the text change directly in the terminal.
如果你不想编辑最后一条消息，你可以用no-edit选项说git commit amend。
And if you don't want to edit the last message, you can just say, git commit amend with the no-edit option.
现在，有一件事我总是试着用两个m来修正
Now, one thing I'm always trying to type in amend with two m's
我不确定你们是否会遇到这个，就像我在git log online时，偶尔我会用git log online，我会漏掉E。
I'm not sure if you'll run into that in the same way that when I do git log oneline, occasionally I'll do git log oneline, I'll miss the E.
我不确定我是怎么了，但有几件事需要注意。
I'm not sure what's happening with me, but just a couple of things to watch out for.
你也可以做所谓的重置。
And you can also do what's called a reset.
重置让您回到之前的提交。
resetting let's you back to a previous commit.
把它想象成一个倒带功能。
And think of that as a rewind feature.
我们可以通过使用日志中的标签来实现，
We can do this by using the hashtags from the log,
所以我们可以说一个git reset，
so we can say something like a git reset,
然后从日志中选择其中一个标签，它会撤销一些更改，
and then select one of these hashtags from the log, and what that will do is it will undo some of the changes,
所以它为我们解除了重置后的变化。
so it unstage the changes after the reset for us.
因此 它实际上是将头部移回另一个提交
So it essentially move back the head to another commit.
现在，它实际上没有对文件做任何事情，所以它没有删除文件，但是它倒回了提交。
Now, it didn't actually do anything to the files, so it didn't delete the files, but it did rewind the commit.
我们再做一次git log online。
So let's do a git a log oneline again.
现在你可以看到 我有三个不同的提交 而不是四个不同的提交
You can see that now, instead of having four different commits, I have three different commits.
所以它停在这里 所以它停在这里
So it stopped right here. So it stopped right there.
现在 很好的一点是 它把所有的文件都恢复到原来的状态
Now, the nice thing is that it took all the files and put them back in their original state.
它没有删除我对这些文件所做的更改
It didn't delete the changes that I have made to these files.
你可以看到，如果我寻找导航，我有我的文本-大写文本，在那里，它显示它们被修改了。
You can see that if I look for the navigation, I have my text-uppercase text, right there, and it shows them as being modified.
我们可以执行git status。
So we can do git status.
注意，我们可以继续添加所有这些文件，
And notice that we can go ahead and add all these files,
我们可以说，git add period, git commit - m然后输入提交信息。
so we can say, git add period, and git commit minus m and type in the commit message.
现在我们有了一个带有新id的新提交。
Now we have a new commit with a new id.
让我们把它清除掉，执行“git log online”命令。
Let's go ahead and clear this out and do a "git log oneline".
我们可以看到 现在我们有了一个带有新消息的新提交
And we can see that now we have a new commit with a new message.
这个命令还有另一个版本
There's another version of this command.
这有点危险，它是带有硬选项的git重置。
It's a little bit dangerous, and it's the git reset with the hard option.
有时候你会看到，
You'll see that sometimes,
你可以输入，git reset - - - hard，然后你输入一个ID。
so you can say, git reset minus minus hard, and then you put in an ID.
这个命令将删除在此之前的所有提交，
This command will delete any commits before this one right here,
它还会更改所有的文件，因此它会删除我所有的更改。
and it'll also change all the files, so it'll actually get rid of all of my changes.
非硬复位或软复位更安全，我建议你试试那个。
The non-hard or the soft reset is a little bit safer, and I suggest that you try that one.
但有时你确实想要重设到一个特定的提交，
But sometimes you do want to sort of reset hard to a specific commit,
让时间倒回到一个特定的检查点，然后从那里继续前进。
to actually rewind time to a specific checkpoint and go forwards from there.
现在，重新定位是另一种改变历史的方式，
Now, rebasing is another way of changing history,
它被设计为从一个分支获取提交并将其应用到另一个分支。
and it's designed to take the commits from one branch and apply them to another.
这是你使用它的方法
Here's the way that you use it.
选择git rebase，然后指定分支或提交。
You select git rebase, and then you specify a branch or a commit.
现在有一个非常有用的交互式命令，它将允许您使用文本编辑器进行更改。
Now there's a really useful interactive command that will let you use your text editor to make changes.
这实际上是使用rebase而不是分支的最好方法，
This is actually the best way to use rebase Instead of a branch,
您可以使用头指针来修改当前分支目录。
you can use the head pointer to modify the current branches directory.
你可以在这里看到
You can see that right here.
我们可以说，git rebase。
So we can say, git rebase.
我希望你通过移回一定数量的提交来重新定位。
And I want you to rebase by moving back to a certain number of commits.
但是，如果你有一个非常长的提交历史，并且你只想回到几个步骤，那么这是有用的。
But that's useful if you have an extremely long commit history and you'll only want to go back a few steps.
还有另一个选项可以让您看到所有提交
There's another option to let you see all the commits.
我们的项目只有很少的提交 所以我们可以安全地使用这个
We have so few commits in our project that we can use this one safely.
比如说，在你完成了一些提交之后，
Let's say, e.g. that after you've done a few commits,
你意识到有些事你应该早点做。
you realize that there's something that you should have done earlier.
我们继续吧，在我执行硬重置之前把这些清理掉。
Let's go ahead, clear this out before I execute that hard reset.
这在这里是很危险的 我们将进入许可证文件
That would be dangerous here. And we'll go into the license file.
我意识到我应该在这里用公司的名字，
And I realized that I should have used the company name here,
所以我要做这个改变。
so I'm going to make that change.
我要保存 添加并提交它
I'm going to save that and add it and commit it.
如果我查看日志，你可以看到我所有的提交都是有序的，
And if I look at the log, you can see that all my commits are in order,
但我真的应该在这里写，对吧
but I really should have done this over here, right
稍微早一点。我应该加上那个修改的。
a little bit earlier. I should have added that modification.
这样我就可以改写历史了
And so I can rewrite the history.
所以这个许可证的更新实际上发生在我第一次提交之后。
So that this updating of the license actually happens after my 1st commit.
所以它发生在这个gitignore文件之前。
So it happened before this gitignore file.
本质上，我可以把这些移动到提交处，
In essence, I can move any of this to commits around,
所有的变化都将在不同的时间点发生。
and all the changes that were in there will happen at a different point in time.
这就像拥有一台时光机
This is exactly like having a time machine.
现在，要做到这一点，让我们继续做一个git rebase。
Now, to do this, let's go ahead and do a git rebase.
我们将做一个交互式版本，我们将使用根目录。
We'll do an interactive version, and we'll use the root.
现在您可以在这里使用头指针，然后返回到，比如说，最后三次提交。
Now you can here use the head pointer, and then just go back to, say, the last three commits.
我们先来试试。
Let's try to that 1st.
这将再次打开我的编辑器，您可以看到我们列出了最后三个提交。
This will open up my editor again, and you can see that we have the last three commits listed.
这里还有很多其他的东西
There's a bunch of other stuff right here.
我马上再给你们看一遍
I'll show you that again in just a 2nd.
让我们退出这个
So let's go ahead and quit this.
如果你只是退出 它不会有任何作用
If you just quit, it doesn't really do anything.
让我们把这些清除掉，
Let's go ahead and clear this out,
我们会用，而不是头3，我们会说，用根选项得到rebase - I。
and we'll use, instead of the head three, we'll just say, get rebase minus i with the root option.
这将为我们带来所有的提交
This will bring us all of our commits.
现在让我们看看你可以在这里执行的选项
And now let's take a look at the options that you can perform right here.
你可以看到我们有第一次提交和所有其他提交的顺序，
You can see that we have the 1st commit and all the other commits in order,
包括我们刚刚执行的这个更新的许可证。
including this updated license that we just performed.
现在 我们要做的是让这个在之前发生 对吧
Now, what we want to do is take this one and make it happen before, right?
这里还有很多其他的选择
And there's a lot of other options that we can perform here.
例如 我们可以通过所谓的壁球提交来修改
So, e.g. we can modify by doing what's called a squash commit.
这将提交这里的任何文件，或任何这些提交，
This would take the commit any of these files right here, or any of these commits,
并将其压缩到之前的提交中。
and squash it into the previous commit.
它会把我们在这里做的和第一次提交结合起来
So it's going to take what we did here and combine it with our 1st commit.
所以就好像每当我创建这个文档时，
So it would be as if whenever I created this document,
它将自动成为第一次提交的一部分，这可能是它应该看起来的方式。
it would automatically be part of this 1st commit, which is probably the way that it should look.
当我第一次加载这个时 它应该看起来已经有了合适的许可证 这样我就可以这样做了
It should look like I had already had the proper license when I 1st loaded this, so I could do that.
还有一个选项叫做修复
And then there's another option called fix up.
这其实很酷 否则它会同时保留两个提交日志消息
And this was actually pretty cool, because otherwise it's going to keep both of the commit logs messages.
我要做的是fixup提交。
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to do a fixup commit.
这就像一个南瓜，
This is like a squash,
它会把这两件事结合起来，但它不会使用提交消息。
it's going to combine these two things, but then it's going to not use the commit message.
让我们保存它 然后关闭它
Let's go ahead and save this, and we'll close this out.
现在我们来看看这个日志
And now let's go ahead and take a look at the log.
因此 您可以看到 我之前对该许可证进行更改的提交已经消失了
So you can see that my previous commit making the change to this license has disappeared.
它实际上被合并到第一次提交中
It's actually been combined into this 1st commit.
因此，您可以看到git rebase是完全重写历史并重新组织提交顺序的绝佳方式。
So you can see that git rebasing is a fantastic way to completely rewrite the history and reorganize the order in which commits are made.